Charles K. Sorensen, MTA Python Developer

3689 Parrish Avenue Victoria, TX 77901 830-994-8344 charlesksorensen@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/charlessorensen

Summary

Motivated PCPP1 and MTA-certified Python developer and professional scrum master with 6+ years of experience. Inclined to bring effectiveness to TechNo's front-end development. Driven by passion and innovation, designed and introduced a new and IAC-award-worthy feature to the MailSent tool. Highly skilled in Python coding and scripting, Django framework, and communication.

Experience

Python Developer

PyMe, Victoria, TX March 2015-present

- Handled programming tasks for and maintained 7 internal websites with a high success rate (97%) in product update deployment.
- Worked on high-impact projects, e.g., content aggregator and expense tracker, delivering solutions with lower than 20% code churn.
- Developed a marketing lead MySQL database, collecting, categorizing, and filtering leads from various stakeholders, i.e., www, social media channels, or newsletters.
- Led sprint planning meetings and divided tasks between a 15-person project team.
- Tutored at three high schools every year, teaching young kids how to code in Python.

Key achievement: Designed a new feature for the company's email marketing tool (MailSent) in 7 Active Days, contributing to the marketing department's win in the IAC award competition in the Best Email Message Campaign category.

Data Scientist

PyMe, Victoria, TX April 2012-February 2015

- Automated and optimized collecting data using SQL, reaching over a 35% system's response time boost.
- Collaborated cross-departmentally on RPA to streamline issue management and migrate the current environments to the cloud, reducing the investment risk by 48%.

Education

2011 M.S. in Engineering

University of Texas, Austin, TX

Skills

- Python, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, SQL
- ORM libraries
- Web frameworks: Django
- MVC and MVT Architecture
- Design skills
- Problem-solving skills
- Communication skills
- Data visualization
- Agile frameworks

Courses and Certificates

- PCPP1 Certified Professional in Python
- MTA 98-381 Microsoft Technical Associate
- PSM II Assessment Certificate Professional Scrum Master

Conferences

- PyCon, every-year attendee since 2018
- DjangoCon, 2020